Daniel Schwindt

9950 Alta Springs Way, Rockville, MD 20850

https://schwindtd.github.io

Professional Summary

Analytically driven financial and economic analyst with 7+ years of experience across economic research, risk management, and financial policy analysis. Highly adaptable with strong project management, programming, quantitative, and organization skills resulting in successful completion of research and risk management projects in fast-paced business environments.

Experience

Federal Reserve Board

January 2024 - Present

Financial Institutions Policy Analyst

Washington, DC

- Research and develop policy proposals for over 100 market and credit risk topics as part of major regulatory initiatives including U.S. Basel III implementation and the transition to central clearing for U.S. treasury securities.
- Manage regulatory capital project timelines across policy, legal, and analytics teams to meet regulatory objectives.
- Prepare and present policy memos and quantitative analysis for governors and senior officers covering both domestic and international bank regulation.
- Lead interagency team analyzing differences in capital standards across federal banking agencies, resulting in publication of annual report to Congress.

University of Maryland

July 2023 - August 2023

Instructor

College Park, MD

- Designed intensive 6-week Summer undergraduate course on macroeconomic theory and policy.
- Prepared and delivered twice weekly two hour lectures to class of 25 students with focus on current economic issues.
- Created series of fifty 10-20 minute videos reviewing key topics such as the Phillips Curve and monetary policy tools.

Morgan Stanley

April 2017 - May 2021

Market Risk Associate

New York, NY

- Designed and analyzed six quarterly market scenarios for capital planning, risk management, and climate frameworks.
- Presented scenario design and risk identification results to senior risk department and business leadership, including the Heads of Market Risk and Risk Capital Planning.
- Performed statistical analysis in R on market data containing 10,000+ variables to inform scenario design decisions.
- Prepared scenario design and counterparty credit risk documentation and senior management reports.

Federal Reserve Board

June 2015 - April 2017

Research Assistant

Washington, DC

- Researched the effects of capital regulation on bank lending in SAS and Stata using loan-level panel datasets.
- Lead team of 8 research assistants in data visualization process for CCAR Scenario Evaluation Team policy memos.
- Analyzed regulatory macroeconomic stress test scenarios in Eviews, Stata, and Excel, resulting in FEDS Note publication measuring scenario severity: (https://doi.org/10.17016/2380-7172.1970).
- Calculated delinquency and loan default rates for key sectors as part of quarterly policy memo to Board of Governors.

Education

University of Maryland

August 2021 - May 2023

Master of Arts in Economics

College Park, MD

GPA: 4.0/4.0

Wake Forest University

August 2011 – May 2015

Bachelor of Science in Mathematical Economics

Winston-Salem. NC

GPA: 3.97/4.0

Technical Skills & Certifications

Programming: MATLAB, R, Stata, Python, Dynare, SAS, SQL, EViews

Technologies/Frameworks: Linux, GitHub, WordPress

Microsoft Office: Excel, Word, PowerPoint

Finance: Financial Engineering & Risk Management (I: March 2021, II: May 2021), Columbia University (Online)